{
    "id": "ecd6f11e61404ba9905373a51112cbae",
    "title": "Conjunctions Quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She was …………………………… frightened ………………………… she could not even move.",
            "description": "So..that.... shows cause and effect.",
            "answers": [
                "so..that...",
                "such...that...",
                "both...and"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. she is rich and influential, she is never rude to anyone.",
            "description": "Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "As",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. we burned the midnight oil, we could not meet the deadline.",
            "description": "Despite and however are not conjunctions. They cannot connect clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Despite",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ill, ……………………….. she is cheerful.",
            "description": "Yet is a conjunction. It can connect clauses. However cannot connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "yet",
                "as",
                "however"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I must obey ………………………… I have no other option.",
            "description": "For can mean because in a very formal or literary style.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "because",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The doorbell rang …………………………. I sat down to rest.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as soon as",
                "no sooner",
                "hardly"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She is industrious ………………………… her brother is lazy.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "whereas",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I moved to a big city …………………………. I might find a better job.",
            "description": "So that indicates purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "so that",
                "such that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It was ………………………… a brilliant performance that the applause lasted at least 10 minutes.",
            "description": "Use such before a noun with an adjective use so before an adjective. ",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "such",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… I didn’t have enough money, I could not buy the tickets.",
            "description": "As gives the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Hence",
                "Though"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. I was driving down the road, I saw Rahul walking his dog.",
            "description": "As can indicate time. It can introduce a longer background action that was going on when another action took place.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "So",
                "Whereas"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They will have to abandon the project ……………………………. you do not support them.",
            "description": "If indicates a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}